{"raw_text":"Amazon (NASDAQ:AMZN) and Whole Foods Market, Inc. (NASDAQ:WFM) today announced that they have entered into a definitive merger agreement under which Amazon will acquire Whole Foods Market for $42 per share in an all-cash transaction valued at approximately $13.7 billion, including Whole Foods Market’s net debt.  “Millions of people love Whole Foods Market because they offer the best natural and organic foods, and they make it fun to eat healthy,” said Jeff Bezos, Amazon founder and CEO. “Whole Foods Market has been satisfying, delighting and nourishing customers for nearly four decades – they’re doing an amazing job and we want that to continue.”  “This partnership presents an opportunity to maximize value for Whole Foods Market’s shareholders, while at the same time extending our mission and bringing the highest quality, experience, convenience and innovation to our customers,” said John Mackey, Whole Foods Market co-founder and CEO.  Whole Foods Market will continue to operate stores under the Whole Foods Market brand and source from trusted vendors and partners around the world. John Mackey will remain as CEO of Whole Foods Market and Whole Foods Market’s headquarters will stay in Austin, Texas.  Completion of the transaction is subject to approval by Whole Foods Market's shareholders, regulatory approvals and other customary closing conditions. The parties expect to close the transaction during the second half of 2017.","metadata":{"keywords":"acquire;acquisition;employs;financing;hire;merger","title":"Amazon to Acquire Whole Foods Market","document_id":"6fc6c430-c97d-46f3-b6a1-f47e0b35e4dc","common_crawl":{"WARC":"1.0","WARC-Type":"response","WARC-Date":"2019-01-23T11:09:42Z","WARC-Record-ID":"<urn:uuid:d4909f36-edf9-41f6-8c77-a8a833642bc2>","Content-Length":"85655","Content-Type":"application\/http; msgtype=response","WARC-Warcinfo-ID":"<urn:uuid:dd532b8c-08b3-40f5-b820-716aaacbce33>","WARC-Concurrent-To":"<urn:uuid:9dd52068-a947-4015-a633-85eb74c82157>","WARC-IP-Address":"184.27.45.187","WARC-Target-URI":"https:\/\/press.aboutamazon.com\/2017\/6\/amazon-to-acquire-whole-foods-market","WARC-Payload-Digest":"sha1:AOSRYAMWY5NUOHGMGC6EEP3R2CTI6AQS","WARC-Block-Digest":"sha1:GXSAKLTY5KE5A7QERVQAMALNC2ZBQP5I","WARC-Identified-Payload-Type":"text\/html"}},"annotations":{"Entities":[{"Mentions":[{"BeginOffset":0,"EndOffset":18,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.998471,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":191,"EndOffset":215,"GroupScore":0.999065,"Score":0.999793,"Text":"Whole Foods Market, Inc.","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":335,"EndOffset":353,"GroupScore":0.512202,"Score":0.999575,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":431,"EndOffset":449,"GroupScore":0.375672,"Score":0.99962,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":487,"EndOffset":505,"GroupScore":0.269334,"Score":0.999789,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":514,"EndOffset":518,"GroupScore":0.213731,"Score":0.924748,"Text":"they","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":565,"EndOffset":569,"GroupScore":0.187103,"Score":0.728192,"Text":"they","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":641,"EndOffset":659,"GroupScore":0.160066,"Score":0.999882,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":743,"EndOffset":747,"GroupScore":0.142373,"Score":0.716707,"Text":"they","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":867,"EndOffset":885,"GroupScore":0.131149,"Score":0.999713,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":1057,"EndOffset":1075,"GroupScore":0.116412,"Score":0.999826,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":1096,"EndOffset":1114,"GroupScore":0.105641,"Score":0.999882,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":1157,"EndOffset":1175,"GroupScore":0.093701,"Score":0.999832,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":1279,"EndOffset":1297,"GroupScore":0.085744,"Score":0.999835,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":1302,"EndOffset":1320,"GroupScore":0.081997,"Score":0.999882,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":1420,"EndOffset":1438,"GroupScore":0.075513,"Score":0.999829,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":2110,"EndOffset":2128,"GroupScore":0.072935,"Score":0.999819,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":2319,"EndOffset":2326,"GroupScore":0.406429,"Score":0.99837,"Text":"Company","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":2437,"EndOffset":2455,"GroupScore":0.999202,"Score":0.99982,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":2686,"EndOffset":2696,"GroupScore":0.535663,"Score":0.99902,"Text":"WholeFoods","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":2765,"EndOffset":2783,"GroupScore":0.396842,"Score":0.999874,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":3140,"EndOffset":3158,"GroupScore":0.295393,"Score":0.999693,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":3976,"EndOffset":3983,"GroupScore":0.253875,"Score":0.999446,"Text":"Company","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":4068,"EndOffset":4075,"GroupScore":0.314292,"Score":0.998088,"Text":"Company","Type":"ORGANIZATION"}]},{"Mentions":[{"BeginOffset":34,"EndOffset":40,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.999375,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":166,"EndOffset":172,"GroupScore":0.999362,"Score":0.999402,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":315,"EndOffset":321,"GroupScore":0.609013,"Score":0.999512,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":616,"EndOffset":622,"GroupScore":0.367933,"Score":0.998879,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":776,"EndOffset":778,"GroupScore":0.266924,"Score":0.997968,"Text":"we","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":1592,"EndOffset":1598,"GroupScore":0.259618,"Score":0.999233,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":1851,"EndOffset":1857,"GroupScore":0.205164,"Score":0.99873,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":1921,"EndOffset":1927,"GroupScore":0.18146,"Score":0.567236,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":1995,"EndOffset":2001,"GroupScore":0.157536,"Score":0.999574,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"}]},{"Mentions":[{"BeginOffset":150,"EndOffset":163,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.999464,"Text":"Jun. 16, 2017","Type":"DATE"},{"BeginOffset":229,"EndOffset":234,"GroupScore":0.99968,"Score":0.998445,"Text":"today","Type":"DATE"}]},{"Mentions":[{"BeginOffset":174,"EndOffset":185,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.997288,"Text":"NASDAQ:AMZN","Type":"STOCK_CODE"}]},{"Mentions":[{"BeginOffset":217,"EndOffset":227,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.99661,"Text":"NASDAQ:WFM","Type":"STOCK_CODE"}]},{"Mentions":[{"BeginOffset":250,"EndOffset":254,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.967192,"Text":"they","Type":"ORGANIZATION"}]},{"Mentions":[{"BeginOffset":1044,"EndOffset":1055,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.999015,"Text":"John Mackey","Type":"PERSON"},{"BeginOffset":1245,"EndOffset":1256,"GroupScore":0.999783,"Score":0.999336,"Text":"John Mackey","Type":"PERSON"}]},{"Mentions":[{"BeginOffset":1272,"EndOffset":1275,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.998567,"Text":"CEO","Type":"PERSON_TITLE"}]},{"Mentions":[{"BeginOffset":1520,"EndOffset":1527,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.96635,"Text":"parties","Type":"ORGANIZATION"}]},{"Mentions":[{"BeginOffset":1560,"EndOffset":1590,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.999712,"Text":"during the second half of 2017","Type":"DATE"}]},{"Mentions":[{"BeginOffset":2709,"EndOffset":2715,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.999344,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":4172,"EndOffset":4178,"GroupScore":0.999096,"Score":0.999512,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":4259,"EndOffset":4265,"GroupScore":0.665541,"Score":0.999467,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":4339,"EndOffset":4345,"GroupScore":0.409646,"Score":0.999649,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"}]},{"Mentions":[{"BeginOffset":5065,"EndOffset":5083,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.999362,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":5325,"EndOffset":5343,"GroupScore":0.999736,"Score":0.999815,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":5732,"EndOffset":5750,"GroupScore":0.514441,"Score":0.999776,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":5929,"EndOffset":5947,"GroupScore":0.393286,"Score":0.999774,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":6060,"EndOffset":6078,"GroupScore":0.279305,"Score":0.999657,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":6190,"EndOffset":6192,"GroupScore":0.222013,"Score":0.669683,"Text":"it","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":6442,"EndOffset":6460,"GroupScore":0.183992,"Score":0.999852,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":6492,"EndOffset":6510,"GroupScore":0.155479,"Score":0.999868,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":6636,"EndOffset":6654,"GroupScore":0.134872,"Score":0.999859,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":6663,"EndOffset":6681,"GroupScore":0.118803,"Score":0.999877,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":6710,"EndOffset":6728,"GroupScore":0.107741,"Score":0.999903,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":6885,"EndOffset":6903,"GroupScore":0.097244,"Score":0.999903,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":7102,"EndOffset":7120,"GroupScore":0.448369,"Score":0.999913,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":7757,"EndOffset":7775,"GroupScore":0.999798,"Score":0.999863,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":7854,"EndOffset":7872,"GroupScore":0.681509,"Score":0.999857,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":7987,"EndOffset":8005,"GroupScore":0.410696,"Score":0.999896,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":8057,"EndOffset":8075,"GroupScore":0.313985,"Score":0.99985,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":8174,"EndOffset":8198,"GroupScore":0.233786,"Score":0.999657,"Text":"Whole Foods Market, Inc.","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":8405,"EndOffset":8423,"GroupScore":0.194,"Score":0.999816,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":8578,"EndOffset":8596,"GroupScore":0.542975,"Score":0.999705,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":8678,"EndOffset":8696,"GroupScore":0.375067,"Score":0.999784,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":8733,"EndOffset":8751,"GroupScore":0.262643,"Score":0.999834,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":8821,"EndOffset":8839,"GroupScore":0.371973,"Score":0.999879,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":8890,"EndOffset":8908,"GroupScore":0.274128,"Score":0.9999,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":9024,"EndOffset":9042,"GroupScore":0.213502,"Score":0.999863,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":9158,"EndOffset":9176,"GroupScore":0.20362,"Score":0.999857,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":9273,"EndOffset":9291,"GroupScore":0.168835,"Score":0.999845,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":9875,"EndOffset":9893,"GroupScore":0.144183,"Score":0.999897,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"}]},{"Mentions":[{"BeginOffset":6102,"EndOffset":6111,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.728341,"Text":"personnel","Type":"PERSON"}]},{"Mentions":[{"BeginOffset":7655,"EndOffset":7664,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.994476,"Text":"Investors","Type":"ORGANIZATION"}]},{"Mentions":[{"BeginOffset":9257,"EndOffset":9269,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.8882,"Text":"participants","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":9646,"EndOffset":9657,"GroupScore":0.950896,"Score":0.841586,"Text":"individuals","Type":"PERSON"}]}],"Events":[{"Arguments":[{"EntityIndex":2,"Role":"ANNOUNCEMENT_DATE","Score":0.998445},{"EntityIndex":5,"Role":"NEW_COMPANY","Score":0.967192},{"EntityIndex":3,"Role":"PARTICIPANT","Score":0.997288},{"EntityIndex":0,"Role":"PARTICIPANT","Score":0.999793},{"EntityIndex":4,"Role":"PARTICIPANT","Score":0.99661},{"EntityIndex":1,"Role":"PARTICIPANT","Score":0.999512}],"Triggers":[{"BeginOffset":286,"EndOffset":292,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.999872,"Text":"merger","Type":"CORPORATE_MERGER"},{"BeginOffset":374,"EndOffset":394,"GroupScore":0.999457,"Score":0.979707,"Text":"all-cash transaction","Type":"CORPORATE_MERGER"},{"BeginOffset":809,"EndOffset":820,"GroupScore":0.511523,"Score":0.999416,"Text":"partnership","Type":"CORPORATE_MERGER"}],"Type":"CORPORATE_MERGER"},{"Arguments":[{"EntityIndex":2,"Role":"ANNOUNCEMENT_DATE","Score":0.998445},{"EntityIndex":0,"Role":"INVESTEE","Score":0.999575},{"EntityIndex":1,"Role":"INVESTOR","Score":0.999512}],"Triggers":[{"BeginOffset":327,"EndOffset":334,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.999345,"Text":"acquire","Type":"CORPORATE_ACQUISITION"}],"Type":"CORPORATE_ACQUISITION"},{"Arguments":[{"EntityIndex":6,"Role":"EMPLOYEE","Score":0.999336},{"EntityIndex":7,"Role":"EMPLOYEE_TITLE","Score":0.998567},{"EntityIndex":0,"Role":"EMPLOYER","Score":0.999835}],"Triggers":[{"BeginOffset":1262,"EndOffset":1268,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.999965,"Text":"remain","Type":"EMPLOYMENT_CHANGE"}],"Type":"EMPLOYMENT_CHANGE"},{"Arguments":[{"EntityIndex":0,"Role":"INVESTEE","Score":0.999829},{"EntityIndex":9,"Role":"INVESTMENT_DATE","Score":0.999712},{"EntityIndex":8,"Role":"INVESTOR","Score":0.96635}],"Triggers":[{"BeginOffset":1382,"EndOffset":1393,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.829322,"Text":"transaction","Type":"INVESTMENT_GENERAL"},{"BeginOffset":1548,"EndOffset":1559,"GroupScore":0.999598,"Score":0.960312,"Text":"transaction","Type":"INVESTMENT_GENERAL"}],"Type":"INVESTMENT_GENERAL"},{"Arguments":[{"EntityIndex":10,"Role":"PARTICIPANT","Score":0.999344},{"EntityIndex":0,"Role":"PARTICIPANT","Score":0.999874}],"Triggers":[{"BeginOffset":2753,"EndOffset":2759,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.999987,"Text":"merger","Type":"CORPORATE_MERGER"},{"BeginOffset":2876,"EndOffset":2882,"GroupScore":0.9988,"Score":0.999989,"Text":"merger","Type":"CORPORATE_MERGER"},{"BeginOffset":2902,"EndOffset":2913,"GroupScore":0.501223,"Score":0.999519,"Text":"transaction","Type":"CORPORATE_MERGER"},{"BeginOffset":2936,"EndOffset":2947,"GroupScore":0.34568,"Score":0.995906,"Text":"transaction","Type":"CORPORATE_MERGER"},{"BeginOffset":4044,"EndOffset":4050,"GroupScore":0.252677,"Score":0.999987,"Text":"merger","Type":"CORPORATE_MERGER"}],"Type":"CORPORATE_MERGER"},{"Arguments":[{"EntityIndex":0,"Role":"INVESTEE","Score":0.999874},{"EntityIndex":10,"Role":"INVESTOR","Score":0.999344}],"Triggers":[{"BeginOffset":2919,"EndOffset":2928,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.995325,"Text":"financing","Type":"INVESTMENT_GENERAL"},{"BeginOffset":3429,"EndOffset":3438,"GroupScore":0.997486,"Score":0.938788,"Text":"financing","Type":"INVESTMENT_GENERAL"}],"Type":"INVESTMENT_GENERAL"},{"Arguments":[{"EntityIndex":11,"Role":"PARTICIPANT","Score":0.999776}],"Triggers":[{"BeginOffset":5676,"EndOffset":5682,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.999972,"Text":"Merger","Type":"CORPORATE_MERGER"},{"BeginOffset":5869,"EndOffset":5875,"GroupScore":0.999238,"Score":0.999975,"Text":"Merger","Type":"CORPORATE_MERGER"},{"BeginOffset":5989,"EndOffset":5995,"GroupScore":0.514127,"Score":0.999969,"Text":"Merger","Type":"CORPORATE_MERGER"},{"BeginOffset":6035,"EndOffset":6041,"GroupScore":0.350876,"Score":0.999977,"Text":"Merger","Type":"CORPORATE_MERGER"}],"Type":"CORPORATE_MERGER"},{"Arguments":[{"EntityIndex":12,"Role":"EMPLOYEE","Score":0.728341},{"EntityIndex":11,"Role":"EMPLOYER","Score":0.999657}],"Triggers":[{"BeginOffset":6093,"EndOffset":6097,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.999907,"Text":"hire","Type":"EMPLOYMENT_CHANGE"}],"Type":"EMPLOYMENT_CHANGE"},{"Arguments":[{"EntityIndex":11,"Role":"INVESTEE","Score":0.999913}],"Triggers":[{"BeginOffset":7089,"EndOffset":7100,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.999936,"Text":"transaction","Type":"INVESTMENT_GENERAL"},{"BeginOffset":7235,"EndOffset":7246,"GroupScore":0.998859,"Score":0.99986,"Text":"transaction","Type":"INVESTMENT_GENERAL"},{"BeginOffset":7482,"EndOffset":7493,"GroupScore":0.424422,"Score":0.995967,"Text":"TRANSACTION","Type":"INVESTMENT_GENERAL"}],"Type":"INVESTMENT_GENERAL"},{"Arguments":[{"EntityIndex":11,"Role":"INVESTEE","Score":0.999863},{"EntityIndex":13,"Role":"INVESTOR","Score":0.994476}],"Triggers":[{"BeginOffset":7598,"EndOffset":7609,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.995176,"Text":"TRANSACTION","Type":"INVESTMENT_GENERAL"},{"BeginOffset":7642,"EndOffset":7653,"GroupScore":0.696194,"Score":0.995651,"Text":"TRANSACTION","Type":"INVESTMENT_GENERAL"}],"Type":"INVESTMENT_GENERAL"},{"Arguments":[{"EntityIndex":11,"Role":"INVESTEE","Score":0.999784},{"EntityIndex":14,"Role":"INVESTOR","Score":0.841586}],"Triggers":[{"BeginOffset":8663,"EndOffset":8674,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.999819,"Text":"acquisition","Type":"CORPORATE_ACQUISITION"},{"BeginOffset":9674,"EndOffset":9685,"GroupScore":0.999651,"Score":0.838081,"Text":"transaction","Type":"INVESTMENT_GENERAL"},{"BeginOffset":9743,"EndOffset":9754,"GroupScore":0.525418,"Score":0.999085,"Text":"acquisition","Type":"CORPORATE_ACQUISITION"}],"Type":"CORPORATE_ACQUISITION"},{"Arguments":[{"EntityIndex":14,"Role":"INVESTOR","Score":0.841586}],"Triggers":[{"BeginOffset":9674,"EndOffset":9685,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.522014,"Text":"transaction","Type":"CORPORATE_ACQUISITION"}],"Type":"CORPORATE_ACQUISITION"}]},"preprocessing":{"level":"char","sentences":[{"start":0,"end":154,"index":0},{"start":155,"end":215,"index":1},{"start":216,"end":224,"index":2},{"start":224,"end":228,"index":3},{"start":229,"end":462,"index":4},{"start":462,"end":639,"index":5},{"start":640,"end":771,"index":6},{"start":772,"end":803,"index":7},{"start":803,"end":1096,"index":8},{"start":1096,"end":1244,"index":9},{"start":1245,"end":1364,"index":10},{"start":1364,"end":1515,"index":11},{"start":1516,"end":1592,"index":12},{"start":1592,"end":1762,"index":13},{"start":1763,"end":2002,"index":14},{"start":2003,"end":2076,"index":15},{"start":2076,"end":2293,"index":16},{"start":2294,"end":2436,"index":17},{"start":2437,"end":2621,"index":18},{"start":2622,"end":2709,"index":19},{"start":2709,"end":2948,"index":20},{"start":2949,"end":3055,"index":21},{"start":3056,"end":4338,"index":22},{"start":4339,"end":4452,"index":23},{"start":4453,"end":4578,"index":24},{"start":4578,"end":4737,"index":25},{"start":4738,"end":5141,"index":26},{"start":5142,"end":5531,"index":27},{"start":5532,"end":6709,"index":28},{"start":6710,"end":6884,"index":29},{"start":6885,"end":7003,"index":30},{"start":7003,"end":7039,"index":31},{"start":7040,"end":7057,"index":32},{"start":7057,"end":7247,"index":33},{"start":7248,"end":7339,"index":34},{"start":7340,"end":7449,"index":35},{"start":7450,"end":7530,"index":36},{"start":7531,"end":7654,"index":37},{"start":7655,"end":7849,"index":38},{"start":7850,"end":7924,"index":39},{"start":7925,"end":8256,"index":40},{"start":8257,"end":8364,"index":41},{"start":8364,"end":8697,"index":42},{"start":8698,"end":9225,"index":43},{"start":9226,"end":9590,"index":44},{"start":9591,"end":9785,"index":45},{"start":9786,"end":9870,"index":46},{"start":9871,"end":9944,"index":47}]},"char_count":9944}
{"raw_text":"Whole Foods Market ranked #28 and Amazon ranked #2 on Fortune’s 2017 list of World’s Most Admired Companies\nSEATTLE & AUSTIN, Texas--(BUSINESS WIRE)--Jun. 16, 2017-- Amazon (NASDAQ:AMZN) and Whole Foods Market, Inc. (NASDAQ:WFM) today announced that they have entered into a definitive merger agreement under which Amazon will acquire Whole Foods Market for per share in an all-cash transaction valued at approximately , including Whole Foods Market’s net debt.\n“Millions of people love Whole Foods Market because they offer the best natural and organic foods, and they make it fun to eat healthy,” said Jeff Bezos, Amazon founder and CEO. “Whole Foods Market has been satisfying, delighting and nourishing customers for nearly four decades – they’re doing an amazing job and we want that to continue.”\n“This partnership presents an opportunity to maximize value for Whole Foods Market’s shareholders, while at the same time extending our mission and bringing the highest quality, experience, convenience and innovation to our customers,” said John Mackey, Whole Foods Market co-founder and CEO.\nWhole Foods Market will continue to operate stores under the Whole Foods Market brand and source from trusted vendors and partners around the world. John Mackey will remain as CEO of Whole Foods Market and Whole Foods Market’s headquarters will stay in Austin, Texas.\nCompletion of the transaction is subject to approval by Whole Foods Market's shareholders, regulatory approvals and other customary closing conditions. The parties expect to close the transaction during the second half of 2017.\nAmazon is guided by four principles: customer obsession rather than competitor focus, passion for invention, commitment to operational excellence, and long-term thinking. Customer reviews, 1-Click shopping, personalized recommendations, Prime, Fulfillment by Amazon, AWS, Kindle Direct Publishing, Kindle, Fire tablets, Fire TV, Amazon Echo, and Alexa are some of the products and services pioneered by Amazon. For more information, visit www.amazon.com\/about and follow @AmazonNews.\nFounded in 1978 in Austin, Texas, Whole Foods Market is the leading natural and organic foods supermarket, the first national “Certified Organic” grocer, and uniquely positioned as America’s Healthiest Grocery Store™. In fiscal year 2016, the Company had sales of approximately and has more than 460 stores in the United States, Canada, and the United Kingdom. Whole Foods Market employs approximately 87,000 team members and has been ranked for 20 consecutive years as one of the “100 Best Companies to Work For” in America by Fortune magazine. For more information, please visit www.WholeFoodsMarket.com or @WholeFoods on Twitter.\nAmazon’s statements related to the proposed merger with Whole Foods Market contain forward-looking statements, including statements regarding expected benefits of the merger, the timing of the transaction, and financing of the transaction. Actual results could differ materially from those projected or forecast in the forward-looking statements. Factors that could cause actual results to differ materially include the following: Whole Foods Market shareholders may not approve the transaction; the conditions to the completion of the transaction may not be satisfied, or the regulatory approvals required for the transaction may not be obtained on the terms expected, on the anticipated schedule, or at all; long-term financing may not be available on favorable terms, or at all; closing of the transaction may not occur or may be delayed, either as a result of litigation related to the transaction or otherwise; the parties may be unable to achieve the anticipated benefits of the transaction; revenues following the transaction may be lower than expected; operating costs, customer loss, and business disruption (including, without limitation, difficulties in maintaining relationships with employees, customers, and suppliers) may be greater than expected; the Company may assume unexpected risks and liabilities; completing the merger may distract the Company’s management from other important matters; and the other factors discussed in “Risk Factors” in Amazon’s Annual Report on Form 10-K for the fiscal year ended December 31, 2016 and in Amazon’s other filings with the SEC, which are available at http:\/\/www.sec.gov. Amazon assumes no obligation to update the information in the communication, except as otherwise required by law. Readers are cautioned not to place undue reliance on these forward-looking statements that speak only as of the date hereof.\nCertain statements in this communication constitute forward-looking statements within the meaning of the U.S. Private Securities Litigation Reform Act of 1995. These forward-looking statements are often identified by words such as “anticipate,” “believe,” “intend,” “estimate,” “expect,” “see,” “continue,” “could,” “can,” “may,” “will,” “likely,” “depend,” “should,” “would,” “plan,” “predict,” “target,” and similar expressions, and may include references to assumptions and relate to Whole Foods Market’s future prospects, developments and business strategies. Except for the historical information contained herein, the matters discussed in this communication are forward-looking statements that involve risks and uncertainties that may cause Whole Foods Market’s actual results to be materially different from such forward-looking statements and could materially adversely affect its business, financial condition, operating results and cash flows. These risks and uncertainties include the occurrence of any event, change or other circumstances that could give rise to the termination of the Merger Agreement; the failure to obtain the approval of Whole Foods Market’s shareholders or required regulatory clearances or the failure to satisfy any of the other closing conditions to the Merger; potential disruption of management’s attention from Whole Foods Market’s ongoing business operations due to the Merger; the effect of the announcement of the Merger on the ability of Whole Foods Market to retain and hire key personnel and maintain relationships with its customers, suppliers and others with whom it does business, or on its operating results and business generally; general business conditions; changes in overall economic conditions that impact consumer spending; the impact of competition; and other factors which are often beyond the control of Whole Foods Market, as well other risks listed in Whole Foods Market’s Annual Report on Form 10-K for the fiscal year ended September 25, 2016 and risks and uncertainties not presently known to Whole Foods Market or that Whole Foods Market currently deems immaterial. Whole Foods Market wishes to caution you that you should not place undue reliance on such forward-looking statements, which speak only as of the date on which they were made. Whole Foods Market does not undertake any obligation to update forward-looking statements, except as required by law.\nImportant Additional Information and Where to Find It\nIn connection with the proposed transaction, Whole Foods Market will file with the SEC and mail or otherwise provide to its shareholders a proxy statement regarding the proposed transaction. BEFORE MAKING ANY VOTING DECISION, WHOLE FOODS MARKET’S SHAREHOLDERS ARE URGED TO CAREFULLY READ THE PROXY STATEMENT IN ITS ENTIRETY WHEN IT BECOMES AVAILABLE AND ANY OTHER DOCUMENTS FILED WITH THE SEC IN CONNECTION WITH THE PROPOSED TRANSACTION OR INCORPORATED BY REFERENCE THEREIN BECAUSE THEY WILL CONTAIN IMPORTANT INFORMATION ABOUT THE PROPOSED TRANSACTION AND THE PARTIES TO THE PROPOSED TRANSACTION. Investors and security holders may obtain a free copy of the proxy statement and other documents that Whole Foods Market files with the SEC (when available) from the SEC’s website at www.sec.gov and Whole Foods Market’s website at http:\/\/investor.wholefoodsmarket.com\/. In addition, the proxy statement and other documents filed by Whole Foods Market with the SEC (when available) may be obtained from Whole Foods Market free of charge by directing a request to Cindy McCann, Global Vice President, Investor Relations, Whole Foods Market, Inc., 550 Bowie Street, Austin, TX 78703, Phone: 512-542-0204. Media inquiries can be directed to Brooke Buchanan at Brooke.Buchanan@wholefoods.com, Phone: 512-542-0751.\nCertain Participants in the Solicitation\nWhole Foods Market, its directors and certain of its executive officers and employees may be deemed, under SEC rules, to be participants in the solicitation of proxies from Whole Foods Market shareholders with respect to shareholder approval of the proposed acquisition of Whole Foods Market. Information regarding the names of Whole Foods Market’s directors and executive officers and their respective interests in Whole Foods Market by security holdings or otherwise is set forth in Whole Foods Market’s Annual Report on Form 10-K for the fiscal year ended September 25, 2016 filed with the SEC on November 18, 2016, Whole Foods Market’s definitive proxy statement for its 2017 Annual Meeting of Shareholders filed with the SEC on January 4, 2017 and Whole Foods Market’s Current Report on Form 8-K dated May 10, 2017. To the extent holdings of such participants in Whole Foods Market’s securities are not reported, or have changed since the amounts described in the proxy statement for the 2017 Annual Meeting of Shareholders, such changes have been reflected on Initial Statements of Beneficial Ownership on Form 3 or Statements of Change in Ownership on Form 4 filed with the SEC. Additional information regarding the interests of such individuals in the proposed transaction will be included in the proxy statement relating to such acquisition when it is filed with the SEC. These documents may be obtained free of charge from the SEC’s website at www.sec.gov and Whole Foods Market’s website at http:\/\/investor.wholefoodsmarket.com.","metadata":{"keywords":"acquire;acquisition;employs;financing;hire;merger","title":"Amazon to Acquire Whole Foods Market","document_id":"6fc6c430-c97d-46f3-b6a1-f47e0b35e4dc","common_crawl":{"WARC":"1.0","WARC-Type":"response","WARC-Date":"2019-01-23T11:09:42Z","WARC-Record-ID":"<urn:uuid:d4909f36-edf9-41f6-8c77-a8a833642bc2>","Content-Length":"85655","Content-Type":"application\/http; msgtype=response","WARC-Warcinfo-ID":"<urn:uuid:dd532b8c-08b3-40f5-b820-716aaacbce33>","WARC-Concurrent-To":"<urn:uuid:9dd52068-a947-4015-a633-85eb74c82157>","WARC-IP-Address":"184.27.45.187","WARC-Target-URI":"https:\/\/press.aboutamazon.com\/news-releases\/news-release-details\/amazon-acquire-whole-foods-market","WARC-Payload-Digest":"sha1:AOSRYAMWY5NUOHGMGC6EEP3R2CTI6AQS","WARC-Block-Digest":"sha1:GXSAKLTY5KE5A7QERVQAMALNC2ZBQP5I","WARC-Identified-Payload-Type":"text\/html"}},"annotations":{"Entities":[{"Mentions":[{"BeginOffset":0,"EndOffset":18,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.998471,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":191,"EndOffset":215,"GroupScore":0.999065,"Score":0.999793,"Text":"Whole Foods Market, Inc.","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":335,"EndOffset":353,"GroupScore":0.512202,"Score":0.999575,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":431,"EndOffset":449,"GroupScore":0.375672,"Score":0.99962,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":487,"EndOffset":505,"GroupScore":0.269334,"Score":0.999789,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":514,"EndOffset":518,"GroupScore":0.213731,"Score":0.924748,"Text":"they","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":565,"EndOffset":569,"GroupScore":0.187103,"Score":0.728192,"Text":"they","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":641,"EndOffset":659,"GroupScore":0.160066,"Score":0.999882,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":743,"EndOffset":747,"GroupScore":0.142373,"Score":0.716707,"Text":"they","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":867,"EndOffset":885,"GroupScore":0.131149,"Score":0.999713,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":1057,"EndOffset":1075,"GroupScore":0.116412,"Score":0.999826,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":1096,"EndOffset":1114,"GroupScore":0.105641,"Score":0.999882,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":1157,"EndOffset":1175,"GroupScore":0.093701,"Score":0.999832,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":1279,"EndOffset":1297,"GroupScore":0.085744,"Score":0.999835,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":1302,"EndOffset":1320,"GroupScore":0.081997,"Score":0.999882,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":1420,"EndOffset":1438,"GroupScore":0.075513,"Score":0.999829,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":2110,"EndOffset":2128,"GroupScore":0.072935,"Score":0.999819,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":2319,"EndOffset":2326,"GroupScore":0.406429,"Score":0.99837,"Text":"Company","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":2437,"EndOffset":2455,"GroupScore":0.999202,"Score":0.99982,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":2686,"EndOffset":2696,"GroupScore":0.535663,"Score":0.99902,"Text":"WholeFoods","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":2765,"EndOffset":2783,"GroupScore":0.396842,"Score":0.999874,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":3140,"EndOffset":3158,"GroupScore":0.295393,"Score":0.999693,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":3976,"EndOffset":3983,"GroupScore":0.253875,"Score":0.999446,"Text":"Company","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":4068,"EndOffset":4075,"GroupScore":0.314292,"Score":0.998088,"Text":"Company","Type":"ORGANIZATION"}]},{"Mentions":[{"BeginOffset":34,"EndOffset":40,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.999375,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":166,"EndOffset":172,"GroupScore":0.999362,"Score":0.999402,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":315,"EndOffset":321,"GroupScore":0.609013,"Score":0.999512,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":616,"EndOffset":622,"GroupScore":0.367933,"Score":0.998879,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":776,"EndOffset":778,"GroupScore":0.266924,"Score":0.997968,"Text":"we","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":1592,"EndOffset":1598,"GroupScore":0.259618,"Score":0.999233,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":1851,"EndOffset":1857,"GroupScore":0.205164,"Score":0.99873,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":1921,"EndOffset":1927,"GroupScore":0.18146,"Score":0.567236,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":1995,"EndOffset":2001,"GroupScore":0.157536,"Score":0.999574,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"}]},{"Mentions":[{"BeginOffset":150,"EndOffset":163,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.999464,"Text":"Jun. 16, 2017","Type":"DATE"},{"BeginOffset":229,"EndOffset":234,"GroupScore":0.99968,"Score":0.998445,"Text":"today","Type":"DATE"}]},{"Mentions":[{"BeginOffset":174,"EndOffset":185,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.997288,"Text":"NASDAQ:AMZN","Type":"STOCK_CODE"}]},{"Mentions":[{"BeginOffset":217,"EndOffset":227,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.99661,"Text":"NASDAQ:WFM","Type":"STOCK_CODE"}]},{"Mentions":[{"BeginOffset":250,"EndOffset":254,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.967192,"Text":"they","Type":"ORGANIZATION"}]},{"Mentions":[{"BeginOffset":1044,"EndOffset":1055,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.999015,"Text":"John Mackey","Type":"PERSON"},{"BeginOffset":1245,"EndOffset":1256,"GroupScore":0.999783,"Score":0.999336,"Text":"John Mackey","Type":"PERSON"}]},{"Mentions":[{"BeginOffset":1272,"EndOffset":1275,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.998567,"Text":"CEO","Type":"PERSON_TITLE"}]},{"Mentions":[{"BeginOffset":1520,"EndOffset":1527,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.96635,"Text":"parties","Type":"ORGANIZATION"}]},{"Mentions":[{"BeginOffset":1560,"EndOffset":1590,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.999712,"Text":"during the second half of 2017","Type":"DATE"}]},{"Mentions":[{"BeginOffset":2709,"EndOffset":2715,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.999344,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":4172,"EndOffset":4178,"GroupScore":0.999096,"Score":0.999512,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":4259,"EndOffset":4265,"GroupScore":0.665541,"Score":0.999467,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":4339,"EndOffset":4345,"GroupScore":0.409646,"Score":0.999649,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"}]},{"Mentions":[{"BeginOffset":5065,"EndOffset":5083,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.999362,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":5325,"EndOffset":5343,"GroupScore":0.999736,"Score":0.999815,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":5732,"EndOffset":5750,"GroupScore":0.514441,"Score":0.999776,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":5929,"EndOffset":5947,"GroupScore":0.393286,"Score":0.999774,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":6060,"EndOffset":6078,"GroupScore":0.279305,"Score":0.999657,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":6190,"EndOffset":6192,"GroupScore":0.222013,"Score":0.669683,"Text":"it","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":6442,"EndOffset":6460,"GroupScore":0.183992,"Score":0.999852,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":6492,"EndOffset":6510,"GroupScore":0.155479,"Score":0.999868,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":6636,"EndOffset":6654,"GroupScore":0.134872,"Score":0.999859,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":6663,"EndOffset":6681,"GroupScore":0.118803,"Score":0.999877,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":6710,"EndOffset":6728,"GroupScore":0.107741,"Score":0.999903,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":6885,"EndOffset":6903,"GroupScore":0.097244,"Score":0.999903,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":7102,"EndOffset":7120,"GroupScore":0.448369,"Score":0.999913,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":7757,"EndOffset":7775,"GroupScore":0.999798,"Score":0.999863,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":7854,"EndOffset":7872,"GroupScore":0.681509,"Score":0.999857,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":7987,"EndOffset":8005,"GroupScore":0.410696,"Score":0.999896,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":8057,"EndOffset":8075,"GroupScore":0.313985,"Score":0.99985,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":8174,"EndOffset":8198,"GroupScore":0.233786,"Score":0.999657,"Text":"Whole Foods Market, Inc.","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":8405,"EndOffset":8423,"GroupScore":0.194,"Score":0.999816,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":8578,"EndOffset":8596,"GroupScore":0.542975,"Score":0.999705,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":8678,"EndOffset":8696,"GroupScore":0.375067,"Score":0.999784,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":8733,"EndOffset":8751,"GroupScore":0.262643,"Score":0.999834,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":8821,"EndOffset":8839,"GroupScore":0.371973,"Score":0.999879,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":8890,"EndOffset":8908,"GroupScore":0.274128,"Score":0.9999,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":9024,"EndOffset":9042,"GroupScore":0.213502,"Score":0.999863,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":9158,"EndOffset":9176,"GroupScore":0.20362,"Score":0.999857,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":9273,"EndOffset":9291,"GroupScore":0.168835,"Score":0.999845,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":9875,"EndOffset":9893,"GroupScore":0.144183,"Score":0.999897,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"}]},{"Mentions":[{"BeginOffset":6102,"EndOffset":6111,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.728341,"Text":"personnel","Type":"PERSON"}]},{"Mentions":[{"BeginOffset":7655,"EndOffset":7664,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.994476,"Text":"Investors","Type":"ORGANIZATION"}]},{"Mentions":[{"BeginOffset":9257,"EndOffset":9269,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.8882,"Text":"participants","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":9646,"EndOffset":9657,"GroupScore":0.950896,"Score":0.841586,"Text":"individuals","Type":"PERSON"}]}],"Events":[{"Arguments":[{"EntityIndex":2,"Role":"ANNOUNCEMENT_DATE","Score":0.998445},{"EntityIndex":5,"Role":"NEW_COMPANY","Score":0.967192},{"EntityIndex":3,"Role":"PARTICIPANT","Score":0.997288},{"EntityIndex":0,"Role":"PARTICIPANT","Score":0.999793},{"EntityIndex":4,"Role":"PARTICIPANT","Score":0.99661},{"EntityIndex":1,"Role":"PARTICIPANT","Score":0.999512}],"Triggers":[{"BeginOffset":286,"EndOffset":292,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.999872,"Text":"merger","Type":"CORPORATE_MERGER"},{"BeginOffset":374,"EndOffset":394,"GroupScore":0.999457,"Score":0.979707,"Text":"all-cash transaction","Type":"CORPORATE_MERGER"},{"BeginOffset":809,"EndOffset":820,"GroupScore":0.511523,"Score":0.999416,"Text":"partnership","Type":"CORPORATE_MERGER"}],"Type":"CORPORATE_MERGER"},{"Arguments":[{"EntityIndex":2,"Role":"ANNOUNCEMENT_DATE","Score":0.998445},{"EntityIndex":0,"Role":"INVESTEE","Score":0.999575},{"EntityIndex":1,"Role":"INVESTOR","Score":0.999512}],"Triggers":[{"BeginOffset":327,"EndOffset":334,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.999345,"Text":"acquire","Type":"CORPORATE_ACQUISITION"}],"Type":"CORPORATE_ACQUISITION"},{"Arguments":[{"EntityIndex":6,"Role":"EMPLOYEE","Score":0.999336},{"EntityIndex":7,"Role":"EMPLOYEE_TITLE","Score":0.998567},{"EntityIndex":0,"Role":"EMPLOYER","Score":0.999835}],"Triggers":[{"BeginOffset":1262,"EndOffset":1268,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.999965,"Text":"remain","Type":"EMPLOYMENT_CHANGE"}],"Type":"EMPLOYMENT_CHANGE"},{"Arguments":[{"EntityIndex":0,"Role":"INVESTEE","Score":0.999829},{"EntityIndex":9,"Role":"INVESTMENT_DATE","Score":0.999712},{"EntityIndex":8,"Role":"INVESTOR","Score":0.96635}],"Triggers":[{"BeginOffset":1382,"EndOffset":1393,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.829322,"Text":"transaction","Type":"INVESTMENT_GENERAL"},{"BeginOffset":1548,"EndOffset":1559,"GroupScore":0.999598,"Score":0.960312,"Text":"transaction","Type":"INVESTMENT_GENERAL"}],"Type":"INVESTMENT_GENERAL"},{"Arguments":[{"EntityIndex":10,"Role":"PARTICIPANT","Score":0.999344},{"EntityIndex":0,"Role":"PARTICIPANT","Score":0.999874}],"Triggers":[{"BeginOffset":2753,"EndOffset":2759,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.999987,"Text":"merger","Type":"CORPORATE_MERGER"},{"BeginOffset":2876,"EndOffset":2882,"GroupScore":0.9988,"Score":0.999989,"Text":"merger","Type":"CORPORATE_MERGER"},{"BeginOffset":2902,"EndOffset":2913,"GroupScore":0.501223,"Score":0.999519,"Text":"transaction","Type":"CORPORATE_MERGER"},{"BeginOffset":2936,"EndOffset":2947,"GroupScore":0.34568,"Score":0.995906,"Text":"transaction","Type":"CORPORATE_MERGER"},{"BeginOffset":4044,"EndOffset":4050,"GroupScore":0.252677,"Score":0.999987,"Text":"merger","Type":"CORPORATE_MERGER"}],"Type":"CORPORATE_MERGER"},{"Arguments":[{"EntityIndex":0,"Role":"INVESTEE","Score":0.999874},{"EntityIndex":10,"Role":"INVESTOR","Score":0.999344}],"Triggers":[{"BeginOffset":2919,"EndOffset":2928,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.995325,"Text":"financing","Type":"INVESTMENT_GENERAL"},{"BeginOffset":3429,"EndOffset":3438,"GroupScore":0.997486,"Score":0.938788,"Text":"financing","Type":"INVESTMENT_GENERAL"}],"Type":"INVESTMENT_GENERAL"},{"Arguments":[{"EntityIndex":11,"Role":"PARTICIPANT","Score":0.999776}],"Triggers":[{"BeginOffset":5676,"EndOffset":5682,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.999972,"Text":"Merger","Type":"CORPORATE_MERGER"},{"BeginOffset":5869,"EndOffset":5875,"GroupScore":0.999238,"Score":0.999975,"Text":"Merger","Type":"CORPORATE_MERGER"},{"BeginOffset":5989,"EndOffset":5995,"GroupScore":0.514127,"Score":0.999969,"Text":"Merger","Type":"CORPORATE_MERGER"},{"BeginOffset":6035,"EndOffset":6041,"GroupScore":0.350876,"Score":0.999977,"Text":"Merger","Type":"CORPORATE_MERGER"}],"Type":"CORPORATE_MERGER"},{"Arguments":[{"EntityIndex":12,"Role":"EMPLOYEE","Score":0.728341},{"EntityIndex":11,"Role":"EMPLOYER","Score":0.999657}],"Triggers":[{"BeginOffset":6093,"EndOffset":6097,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.999907,"Text":"hire","Type":"EMPLOYMENT_CHANGE"}],"Type":"EMPLOYMENT_CHANGE"},{"Arguments":[{"EntityIndex":11,"Role":"INVESTEE","Score":0.999913}],"Triggers":[{"BeginOffset":7089,"EndOffset":7100,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.999936,"Text":"transaction","Type":"INVESTMENT_GENERAL"},{"BeginOffset":7235,"EndOffset":7246,"GroupScore":0.998859,"Score":0.99986,"Text":"transaction","Type":"INVESTMENT_GENERAL"},{"BeginOffset":7482,"EndOffset":7493,"GroupScore":0.424422,"Score":0.995967,"Text":"TRANSACTION","Type":"INVESTMENT_GENERAL"}],"Type":"INVESTMENT_GENERAL"},{"Arguments":[{"EntityIndex":11,"Role":"INVESTEE","Score":0.999863},{"EntityIndex":13,"Role":"INVESTOR","Score":0.994476}],"Triggers":[{"BeginOffset":7598,"EndOffset":7609,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.995176,"Text":"TRANSACTION","Type":"INVESTMENT_GENERAL"},{"BeginOffset":7642,"EndOffset":7653,"GroupScore":0.696194,"Score":0.995651,"Text":"TRANSACTION","Type":"INVESTMENT_GENERAL"}],"Type":"INVESTMENT_GENERAL"},{"Arguments":[{"EntityIndex":11,"Role":"INVESTEE","Score":0.999784},{"EntityIndex":14,"Role":"INVESTOR","Score":0.841586}],"Triggers":[{"BeginOffset":8663,"EndOffset":8674,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.999819,"Text":"acquisition","Type":"CORPORATE_ACQUISITION"},{"BeginOffset":9674,"EndOffset":9685,"GroupScore":0.999651,"Score":0.838081,"Text":"transaction","Type":"INVESTMENT_GENERAL"},{"BeginOffset":9743,"EndOffset":9754,"GroupScore":0.525418,"Score":0.999085,"Text":"acquisition","Type":"CORPORATE_ACQUISITION"}],"Type":"CORPORATE_ACQUISITION"},{"Arguments":[{"EntityIndex":14,"Role":"INVESTOR","Score":0.841586}],"Triggers":[{"BeginOffset":9674,"EndOffset":9685,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.522014,"Text":"transaction","Type":"CORPORATE_ACQUISITION"}],"Type":"CORPORATE_ACQUISITION"}]},"preprocessing":{"level":"char","sentences":[{"start":0,"end":154,"index":0},{"start":155,"end":215,"index":1},{"start":216,"end":224,"index":2},{"start":224,"end":228,"index":3},{"start":229,"end":462,"index":4},{"start":462,"end":639,"index":5},{"start":640,"end":771,"index":6},{"start":772,"end":803,"index":7},{"start":803,"end":1096,"index":8},{"start":1096,"end":1244,"index":9},{"start":1245,"end":1364,"index":10},{"start":1364,"end":1515,"index":11},{"start":1516,"end":1592,"index":12},{"start":1592,"end":1762,"index":13},{"start":1763,"end":2002,"index":14},{"start":2003,"end":2076,"index":15},{"start":2076,"end":2293,"index":16},{"start":2294,"end":2436,"index":17},{"start":2437,"end":2621,"index":18},{"start":2622,"end":2709,"index":19},{"start":2709,"end":2948,"index":20},{"start":2949,"end":3055,"index":21},{"start":3056,"end":4338,"index":22},{"start":4339,"end":4452,"index":23},{"start":4453,"end":4578,"index":24},{"start":4578,"end":4737,"index":25},{"start":4738,"end":5141,"index":26},{"start":5142,"end":5531,"index":27},{"start":5532,"end":6709,"index":28},{"start":6710,"end":6884,"index":29},{"start":6885,"end":7003,"index":30},{"start":7003,"end":7039,"index":31},{"start":7040,"end":7057,"index":32},{"start":7057,"end":7247,"index":33},{"start":7248,"end":7339,"index":34},{"start":7340,"end":7449,"index":35},{"start":7450,"end":7530,"index":36},{"start":7531,"end":7654,"index":37},{"start":7655,"end":7849,"index":38},{"start":7850,"end":7924,"index":39},{"start":7925,"end":8256,"index":40},{"start":8257,"end":8364,"index":41},{"start":8364,"end":8697,"index":42},{"start":8698,"end":9225,"index":43},{"start":9226,"end":9590,"index":44},{"start":9591,"end":9785,"index":45},{"start":9786,"end":9870,"index":46},{"start":9871,"end":9944,"index":47}]},"char_count":9944}
{"raw_text":"SEATTLE & AUSTIN, Texas--(BUSINESS WIRE)--Aug. 24, 2017-- (NASDAQ:AMZN)—Amazon and Whole Foods Market today announced that Amazon’s acquisition of Whole Foods Market will close on Monday August 28, 2017, and the two companies will together pursue the vision of making Whole Foods Market’s high-quality, natural and organic food affordable for everyone. As a down payment on that vision, Whole Foods Market will offer lower prices starting Monday on a selection of best-selling grocery staples across its stores, with more to come.\nIn addition, Amazon and Whole Foods Market technology teams will begin to integrate Amazon Prime into the Whole Foods Market point-of-sale system, and when this work is complete, Prime members will receive special savings and in-store benefits. The two companies will invent in additional areas over time, including in merchandising and logistics, to enable lower prices for Whole Foods Market customers.\n“We’re determined to make healthy and organic food affordable for everyone. Everybody should be able to eat Whole Foods Market quality – we will lower prices without compromising Whole Foods Market’s long-held commitment to the highest standards,” said Jeff Wilke, CEO of Amazon Worldwide Consumer. “To get started, we’re going to lower prices beginning Monday on a selection of best-selling grocery staples, including Whole Trade organic bananas, responsibly-farmed salmon, organic large brown eggs, animal-welfare-rated 85% lean ground beef, and more. And this is just the beginning – we will make Amazon Prime the customer rewards program at Whole Foods Market and continuously lower prices as we invent together. There is significant work and opportunity ahead, and we’re thrilled to get started.”\n“It’s been our mission for 39 years at Whole Foods Market to bring the highest quality food to our customers,” said John Mackey, Whole Foods Market co-founder and CEO. “By working together with Amazon and integrating in several key areas, we can lower prices and double down on that mission and reach more people with Whole Foods Market’s high-quality, natural and organic food. As part of our commitment to quality, we’ll continue to expand our efforts to support and promote local products and suppliers. We can’t wait to start showing customers what’s possible when Whole Foods Market and Amazon innovate together.”\nHere’s what will be new in Whole Foods Market stores on Monday and what customers can expect over time as the two companies integrate:\n• Starting Monday, Whole Foods Market will offer lower prices on a selection of best-selling staples across its stores, with much more to come. Customers will enjoy lower prices on products like Whole Trade bananas, organic avocados, organic large brown eggs, organic responsibly-farmed salmon and tilapia, organic baby kale and baby lettuce, animal-welfare-rated 85% lean ground beef, creamy and crunchy almond butter, organic Gala and Fuji apples, organic rotisserie chicken, 365 Everyday Value organic butter, and much more.\n• In the future, after certain technical integration work is complete, Amazon Prime will become Whole Foods Market’s customer rewards program, providing Prime members with special savings and other in-store benefits.\n• Whole Foods Market’s healthy and high-quality private label products—including 365 Everyday Value, Whole Foods Market, Whole Paws and Whole Catch—will be available through Amazon.com, AmazonFresh, Prime Pantry and Prime Now.\n• Amazon Lockers will be available in select Whole Foods Market stores. Customers can have products shipped from Amazon.com to their local Whole Foods Market store for pick up or send returns back to Amazon during a trip to the store.\nThis is just the beginning – Amazon and Whole Foods Market plan to offer more in-store benefits and lower prices for customers over time as the two companies integrate logistics and point-of-sale and merchandising systems.\nWhole Foods Market will continue to grow its team and create jobs in local communities as it opens new stores, hires new team members, and expands its support of local farmers and artisans. The company will maintain operations under the Whole Foods Market brand, preserve its high standards and commitment to providing the finest natural and organic foods, and continue to source from trusted vendors and partners around the world. John Mackey will remain as CEO and Whole Foods Market’s headquarters will stay in Austin, Texas.\nAmazon is guided by four principles: customer obsession rather than competitor focus, passion for invention, commitment to operational excellence, and long-term thinking. Customer reviews, 1-Click shopping, personalized recommendations, Prime, Fulfillment by Amazon, AWS, Kindle Direct Publishing, Kindle, Fire tablets, Fire TV, Amazon Echo, and Alexa are some of the products and services pioneered by Amazon. For more information, visit www.amazon.com\/about and follow @AmazonNews.\nFounded in 1978 in Austin, Texas, Whole Foods Market is the leading natural and organic foods supermarket, the first national “Certified Organic” grocer, and uniquely positioned as America’s Healthiest Grocery Store. In fiscal year 2016, the Company had sales of approximately and has more than 460 stores in the United States, Canada, and the United Kingdom. Whole Foods Market employs approximately 87,000 team members and has been ranked for 20 consecutive years as one of the “100 Best Companies to Work For” in America by Fortune magazine. For more information, please visit www.WholeFoodsMarket.com or @WholeFoods on Twitter.\nThis communication contains forward-looking statements. We use words such as anticipates, believes, expects, future, intends, and similar expressions to identify forward-looking statements. Actual results could differ materially from those projected or forecast in the forward-looking statements. Factors that could cause actual results to differ materially include the following: factors that could affect the timing of the consummation of Amazon’s acquisition of Whole Foods Market; Amazon may be unable to achieve the anticipated benefits of the transaction; revenues following the transaction may be lower than expected; operating costs, customer loss, and business disruption (including, without limitation, difficulties in maintaining relationships with employees, customers, and suppliers) may be greater than expected; Amazon may assume unexpected risks and liabilities; initiatives with Whole Foods Market may distract Amazon’s management from other operations; and the other factors discussed in “Risk Factors” in Amazon’s Annual Report on Form 10-K for the fiscal year ended December 31, 2016 and in Amazon’s other filings with the SEC, which are available at http:\/\/www.sec.gov. Amazon assumes no obligation to update the information in this communication, except as otherwise required by law. Readers are cautioned not to place undue reliance on these forward-looking statements that speak only as of the date hereof.","metadata":{"keywords":"acquisition;employs","title":"Amazon and Whole Foods Market Announce Acquisition to Close This Monday, Will Work Together to Make High-Quality, Natural and Organic Food Affordable for Everyone","document_id":"0cdf6deb-78c7-4900-b7e0-76053bb4a7cb","common_crawl":{"WARC":"1.0","WARC-Type":"response","WARC-Date":"2019-01-23T11:27:06Z","WARC-Record-ID":"<urn:uuid:e77e87d7-b556-40db-83e7-f0510b82da22>","Content-Length":"82697","Content-Type":"application\/http; msgtype=response","WARC-Warcinfo-ID":"<urn:uuid:d7b39b09-8bb5-4614-ba2a-5aa110e1a544>","WARC-Concurrent-To":"<urn:uuid:06692994-ab75-465c-8c1e-19366c78a251>","WARC-IP-Address":"184.27.45.7","WARC-Target-URI":"https:\/\/press.aboutamazon.com\/news-releases\/news-release-details\/amazon-and-whole-foods-market-announce-acquisition-close-monday","WARC-Payload-Digest":"sha1:KRDTZV7BMDFW3YLDRNBYHMVKOFOAKQTI","WARC-Block-Digest":"sha1:VVMORHAFS7KO4G3BYA67A4KH2NSWZLHE","WARC-Identified-Payload-Type":"text\/html"}},"annotations":{"Entities":[{"Mentions":[{"BeginOffset":83,"EndOffset":101,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.999904,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":147,"EndOffset":165,"GroupScore":0.999393,"Score":0.999883,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":268,"EndOffset":286,"GroupScore":0.519939,"Score":0.999862,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":387,"EndOffset":405,"GroupScore":0.345411,"Score":0.999844,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":555,"EndOffset":573,"GroupScore":0.26532,"Score":0.999855,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":637,"EndOffset":655,"GroupScore":0.225615,"Score":0.999717,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":906,"EndOffset":924,"GroupScore":0.188121,"Score":0.999762,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":937,"EndOffset":939,"GroupScore":0.154788,"Score":0.996531,"Text":"We","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":1044,"EndOffset":1062,"GroupScore":0.145416,"Score":0.999833,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":1073,"EndOffset":1075,"GroupScore":0.134348,"Score":0.976744,"Text":"we","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":1115,"EndOffset":1133,"GroupScore":0.112759,"Score":0.999822,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":1252,"EndOffset":1254,"GroupScore":0.113041,"Score":0.998507,"Text":"we","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":1355,"EndOffset":1366,"GroupScore":0.091604,"Score":0.910312,"Text":"Whole Trade","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":1523,"EndOffset":1525,"GroupScore":0.101808,"Score":0.99682,"Text":"we","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":1581,"EndOffset":1599,"GroupScore":0.078955,"Score":0.99978,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":1633,"EndOffset":1635,"GroupScore":0.078234,"Score":0.990116,"Text":"we","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":1706,"EndOffset":1708,"GroupScore":0.075598,"Score":0.998128,"Text":"we","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":1777,"EndOffset":1795,"GroupScore":0.07111,"Score":0.999752,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":1867,"EndOffset":1885,"GroupScore":0.066828,"Score":0.999599,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":1977,"EndOffset":1979,"GroupScore":0.060722,"Score":0.997643,"Text":"we","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":2056,"EndOffset":2074,"GroupScore":0.059748,"Score":0.999769,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":2155,"EndOffset":2157,"GroupScore":0.05562,"Score":0.982883,"Text":"we","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":2245,"EndOffset":2247,"GroupScore":0.373996,"Score":0.998315,"Text":"We","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":2307,"EndOffset":2325,"GroupScore":0.225098,"Score":0.999854,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":2384,"EndOffset":2402,"GroupScore":0.511629,"Score":0.999628,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":2511,"EndOffset":2529,"GroupScore":0.364596,"Score":0.999813,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":2687,"EndOffset":2698,"GroupScore":0.267618,"Score":0.995965,"Text":"Whole Trade","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":3116,"EndOffset":3134,"GroupScore":0.240163,"Score":0.999835,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":3239,"EndOffset":3257,"GroupScore":0.252152,"Score":0.999767,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":3338,"EndOffset":3356,"GroupScore":0.207393,"Score":0.996123,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":3509,"EndOffset":3527,"GroupScore":0.177552,"Score":0.998858,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":3603,"EndOffset":3621,"GroupScore":0.171663,"Score":0.99952,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":3739,"EndOffset":3757,"GroupScore":0.142901,"Score":0.999808,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":3922,"EndOffset":3940,"GroupScore":0.125077,"Score":0.999842,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":4012,"EndOffset":4014,"GroupScore":0.110933,"Score":0.952261,"Text":"it","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":4116,"EndOffset":4123,"GroupScore":0.09891,"Score":0.999129,"Text":"company","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":4159,"EndOffset":4177,"GroupScore":0.096362,"Score":0.9998,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":4389,"EndOffset":4407,"GroupScore":0.086047,"Score":0.999845,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"}]},{"Mentions":[{"BeginOffset":123,"EndOffset":129,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.999529,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":544,"EndOffset":550,"GroupScore":0.999163,"Score":0.999574,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":1536,"EndOffset":1542,"GroupScore":0.569984,"Score":0.987852,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":1932,"EndOffset":1938,"GroupScore":0.405091,"Score":0.999222,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":2330,"EndOffset":2336,"GroupScore":0.68519,"Score":0.999516,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":3411,"EndOffset":3421,"GroupScore":0.984219,"Score":0.99946,"Text":"Amazon.com","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":3466,"EndOffset":3472,"GroupScore":0.57516,"Score":0.998033,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":3577,"EndOffset":3587,"GroupScore":0.579435,"Score":0.999665,"Text":"Amazon.com","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":3664,"EndOffset":3670,"GroupScore":0.360524,"Score":0.999326,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":3728,"EndOffset":3734,"GroupScore":0.280418,"Score":0.999617,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":4451,"EndOffset":4457,"GroupScore":0.618784,"Score":0.999203,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":4710,"EndOffset":4716,"GroupScore":0.999566,"Score":0.998385,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":4854,"EndOffset":4860,"GroupScore":0.560726,"Score":0.999499,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":6008,"EndOffset":6014,"GroupScore":0.348414,"Score":0.999534,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":6052,"EndOffset":6058,"GroupScore":0.275166,"Score":0.999635,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":6394,"EndOffset":6400,"GroupScore":0.243239,"Score":0.999705,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":6495,"EndOffset":6501,"GroupScore":0.228778,"Score":0.999284,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":6591,"EndOffset":6597,"GroupScore":0.197381,"Score":0.999526,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":6678,"EndOffset":6684,"GroupScore":0.172745,"Score":0.999053,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":6758,"EndOffset":6764,"GroupScore":0.375186,"Score":0.999521,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"}]},{"Mentions":[{"BeginOffset":177,"EndOffset":202,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.999754,"Text":"on Monday August 28, 2017","Type":"DATE"}]},{"Mentions":[{"BeginOffset":2450,"EndOffset":2459,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.936475,"Text":"over time","Type":"DATE"},{"BeginOffset":3826,"EndOffset":3835,"GroupScore":0.996381,"Score":0.953689,"Text":"over time","Type":"DATE"}]},{"Mentions":[{"BeginOffset":2471,"EndOffset":2480,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.99692,"Text":"companies","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":3847,"EndOffset":3856,"GroupScore":0.999541,"Score":0.996161,"Text":"companies","Type":"ORGANIZATION"}]},{"Mentions":[{"BeginOffset":4048,"EndOffset":4055,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.690648,"Text":"members","Type":"PERSON"}]},{"Mentions":[{"BeginOffset":4354,"EndOffset":4365,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.99959,"Text":"John Mackey","Type":"PERSON"}]},{"Mentions":[{"BeginOffset":4381,"EndOffset":4384,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.998507,"Text":"CEO","Type":"PERSON_TITLE"}]},{"Mentions":[{"BeginOffset":4969,"EndOffset":4987,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.999781,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":5029,"EndOffset":5040,"GroupScore":0.996526,"Score":0.652558,"Text":"supermarket","Type":"FACILITY"},{"BeginOffset":5081,"EndOffset":5087,"GroupScore":0.53123,"Score":0.98585,"Text":"grocer","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":5137,"EndOffset":5150,"GroupScore":0.368986,"Score":0.670476,"Text":"Grocery Store","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":5177,"EndOffset":5184,"GroupScore":0.261034,"Score":0.998697,"Text":"Company","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":5295,"EndOffset":5313,"GroupScore":0.212233,"Score":0.999798,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":5544,"EndOffset":5554,"GroupScore":0.202167,"Score":0.998193,"Text":"WholeFoods","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":5623,"EndOffset":5625,"GroupScore":0.188418,"Score":0.998194,"Text":"We","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":6032,"EndOffset":6050,"GroupScore":0.158267,"Score":0.99975,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":6463,"EndOffset":6481,"GroupScore":0.165002,"Score":0.987945,"Text":"Whole Foods Market","Type":"ORGANIZATION"}]}],"Events":[{"Arguments":[{"EntityIndex":0,"Role":"INVESTEE","Score":0.999883},{"EntityIndex":2,"Role":"INVESTMENT_DATE","Score":0.999754},{"EntityIndex":1,"Role":"INVESTOR","Score":0.999529}],"Triggers":[{"BeginOffset":132,"EndOffset":143,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.999963,"Text":"acquisition","Type":"CORPORATE_ACQUISITION"}],"Type":"CORPORATE_ACQUISITION"},{"Arguments":[{"EntityIndex":3,"Role":"MERGER_DATE","Score":0.936475},{"EntityIndex":4,"Role":"PARTICIPANT","Score":0.99692}],"Triggers":[{"BeginOffset":2481,"EndOffset":2490,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.999042,"Text":"integrate","Type":"CORPORATE_MERGER"}],"Type":"CORPORATE_MERGER"},{"Arguments":[{"EntityIndex":0,"Role":"EMPLOYER","Score":0.999842}],"Triggers":[{"BeginOffset":3958,"EndOffset":3962,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.999834,"Text":"grow","Type":"EMPLOYMENT_CHANGE"}],"Type":"EMPLOYMENT_CHANGE"},{"Arguments":[{"EntityIndex":0,"Role":"EMPLOYER","Score":0.999842}],"Triggers":[{"BeginOffset":3976,"EndOffset":3982,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.999998,"Text":"create","Type":"EMPLOYMENT_CHANGE"}],"Type":"EMPLOYMENT_CHANGE"},{"Arguments":[{"EntityIndex":0,"Role":"EMPLOYER","Score":0.999842}],"Triggers":[{"BeginOffset":3983,"EndOffset":3987,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.790224,"Text":"jobs","Type":"EMPLOYMENT_CHANGE"}],"Type":"EMPLOYMENT_CHANGE"},{"Arguments":[{"EntityIndex":5,"Role":"EMPLOYEE","Score":0.690648},{"EntityIndex":0,"Role":"EMPLOYER","Score":0.952261}],"Triggers":[{"BeginOffset":4033,"EndOffset":4038,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.999998,"Text":"hires","Type":"EMPLOYMENT_CHANGE"}],"Type":"EMPLOYMENT_CHANGE"},{"Arguments":[{"EntityIndex":6,"Role":"EMPLOYEE","Score":0.99959},{"EntityIndex":7,"Role":"EMPLOYEE_TITLE","Score":0.998507},{"EntityIndex":0,"Role":"EMPLOYER","Score":0.999845}],"Triggers":[{"BeginOffset":4366,"EndOffset":4370,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.709769,"Text":"will","Type":"EMPLOYMENT_CHANGE"}],"Type":"EMPLOYMENT_CHANGE"},{"Arguments":[{"EntityIndex":6,"Role":"EMPLOYEE","Score":0.99959},{"EntityIndex":7,"Role":"EMPLOYEE_TITLE","Score":0.998507},{"EntityIndex":0,"Role":"EMPLOYER","Score":0.999845}],"Triggers":[{"BeginOffset":4371,"EndOffset":4377,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.994305,"Text":"remain","Type":"EMPLOYMENT_CHANGE"}],"Type":"EMPLOYMENT_CHANGE"},{"Arguments":[{"EntityIndex":6,"Role":"EMPLOYEE","Score":0.99959},{"EntityIndex":7,"Role":"EMPLOYEE_TITLE","Score":0.998507},{"EntityIndex":0,"Role":"EMPLOYER","Score":0.999845}],"Triggers":[{"BeginOffset":4428,"EndOffset":4432,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.712203,"Text":"stay","Type":"EMPLOYMENT_CHANGE"}],"Type":"EMPLOYMENT_CHANGE"},{"Arguments":[{"EntityIndex":8,"Role":"INVESTEE","Score":0.99975},{"EntityIndex":1,"Role":"INVESTOR","Score":0.999534}],"Triggers":[{"BeginOffset":6017,"EndOffset":6028,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.999911,"Text":"acquisition","Type":"CORPORATE_ACQUISITION"},{"BeginOffset":6116,"EndOffset":6127,"GroupScore":0.999547,"Score":0.999934,"Text":"transaction","Type":"CORPORATE_ACQUISITION"},{"BeginOffset":6152,"EndOffset":6163,"GroupScore":0.519901,"Score":0.999935,"Text":"transaction","Type":"CORPORATE_ACQUISITION"}],"Type":"CORPORATE_ACQUISITION"}]},"preprocessing":{"level":"char","sentences":[{"start":0,"end":17,"index":0},{"start":18,"end":46,"index":1},{"start":47,"end":66,"index":2},{"start":66,"end":352,"index":3},{"start":353,"end":531,"index":4},{"start":531,"end":775,"index":5},{"start":776,"end":936,"index":6},{"start":936,"end":1011,"index":7},{"start":1012,"end":1234,"index":8},{"start":1235,"end":1436,"index":9},{"start":1437,"end":1489,"index":10},{"start":1490,"end":1652,"index":11},{"start":1653,"end":1738,"index":12},{"start":1738,"end":1905,"index":13},{"start":1906,"end":2116,"index":14},{"start":2117,"end":2244,"index":15},{"start":2245,"end":2285,"index":16},{"start":2286,"end":2357,"index":17},{"start":2357,"end":2492,"index":18},{"start":2492,"end":2493,"index":19},{"start":2494,"end":2635,"index":20},{"start":2636,"end":3020,"index":21},{"start":3020,"end":3021,"index":22},{"start":3022,"end":3237,"index":23},{"start":3237,"end":3458,"index":24},{"start":3459,"end":3464,"index":25},{"start":3464,"end":3535,"index":26},{"start":3536,"end":3699,"index":27},{"start":3699,"end":3727,"index":28},{"start":3728,"end":3922,"index":29},{"start":3922,"end":4111,"index":30},{"start":4112,"end":4353,"index":31},{"start":4354,"end":4451,"index":32},{"start":4451,"end":4621,"index":33},{"start":4622,"end":4861,"index":34},{"start":4862,"end":4935,"index":35},{"start":4935,"end":5151,"index":36},{"start":5152,"end":5294,"index":37},{"start":5295,"end":5479,"index":38},{"start":5480,"end":5567,"index":39},{"start":5567,"end":5622,"index":40},{"start":5623,"end":5756,"index":41},{"start":5757,"end":5863,"index":42},{"start":5864,"end":6757,"index":43},{"start":6758,"end":6872,"index":44},{"start":6873,"end":6997,"index":45}]},"char_count":6997}
{"raw_text":"SEATTLE--(BUSINESS WIRE)--Jun. 9, 2016-- Amazon (NASDAQ: AMZN) today announced plans for a new technology development center in downtown Minneapolis that will create 100 full-time, technology-focused jobs. To celebrate Amazon’s expansion in the Minneapolis community, Amazon is donating plus mentoring support to local nonprofit Code Savvy to help the group’s mission of encouraging youth’s understanding of coding and promoting diversity in the technology industry. Amazon currently has hundreds of employees in Minnesota and is in the process of hiring an additional 1,000 full-time employees for its new Shakopee, Minnesota, fulfillment center.\n“Amazon is always looking for the best and brightest software engineers to join our team,” said Dave Glick, vice president of operations technology for Amazon. “The commitment to education, growth of the local high-tech industry, and caliber of technical talent in Minneapolis make it an ideal place for our expansion. We’re excited to create new technology jobs in Minneapolis and look forward to growing our operations technology team to help us develop cutting-edge software applications that fuel Amazon’s rapidly growing operations, fulfillment and delivery capabilities.”\n“On behalf of the City of Minneapolis, it is my pleasure to extend a warm welcome to Amazon,” said Minneapolis Mayor Betsy Hodges. “Minneapolis is growing rapidly, and our expanding workforce is ready for the new full-time, high-technology jobs Amazon will bring. Welcome to our community.”\nThe Minneapolis office will include multiple roles like software development engineers and managers who will be tasked with developing and innovating technology solutions that enhance Amazon’s operations. Amazon employees receive comprehensive benefits, including healthcare, 401(k) and company stock awards, starting on day one, as well as generous maternity and parental leave benefits.\n“I’m excited that Amazon is bringing 100 new, high-tech jobs to Minneapolis,” remarked Representative Raymond Dehn (DFL-Minneapolis). “Not only will they be creating good paying jobs in an area of need, they’ve chosen to donate to Code Savvy, a non-profit that teaches inner-city kids to code so they may have a better future. Minneapolis has been a leader in technology and I’m pleased to welcome Amazon to our community.”\nAs part of the company’s expansion in Minneapolis and its commitment to the local community, Amazon will be donating to Code Savvy to fund the nonprofit’s Technovation[MN] program. The program focuses on technology entrepreneurship led by girls that helps participants build problem-solving apps and create business plans. Amazon employees at the new office will also be offering mentoring support to Code Savvy.\n“Code Savvy is so thrilled that Amazon is expanding their technology team to the Minneapolis area and has honored us with a donation to our all-girl entrepreneurship and app development program, Technovation[MN]. Welcome to the Code Savvy community!” said Jean Weiss, executive director of Code Savvy. “In addition to this much needed funding, we are looking forward to the Amazon team participating as mentors in the program and hosting teams on field trips at their sites. Our thriving tech community will be a great place for Amazon’s expanded venture and we look forward to working closely with them on this and other Code Savvy programs going forward.”\nTo learn more about job opportunities with Amazon in Minnesota, visit www.amazon.jobs\/minneapolis-mn.\nAmazon.com opened on the World Wide Web in July 1995. The company is guided by four principles: customer obsession rather than competitor focus, passion for invention, commitment to operational excellence, and long-term thinking. Customer reviews, 1-Click shopping, personalized recommendations, Prime, Fulfillment by Amazon, AWS, Kindle Direct Publishing, Kindle, Fire tablets, Fire TV, Amazon Echo, and Alexa are some of the products and services pioneered by Amazon. For more information, visit www.amazon.com\/about.","metadata":{"keywords":"hiring","title":"Amazon to Open Office in Minneapolis and Create 100 Full-Time, Technology-Focused Jobs","document_id":"15507b0f-0f23-4d91-94cb-4defa3d9153a","common_crawl":{"WARC":"1.0","WARC-Type":"response","WARC-Date":"2019-01-23T11:57:23Z","WARC-Record-ID":"<urn:uuid:8b78c23c-b863-4c7e-a133-893965f4081f>","Content-Length":"77414","Content-Type":"application\/http; msgtype=response","WARC-Warcinfo-ID":"<urn:uuid:41e56a23-abfd-4929-865d-46c2b66e5b5a>","WARC-Concurrent-To":"<urn:uuid:847dd41e-f013-4316-b0ce-6bf7d1a0bb0c>","WARC-IP-Address":"184.28.17.138","WARC-Target-URI":"https:\/\/press.aboutamazon.com\/news-releases\/news-release-details\/amazon-open-office-minneapolis-and-create-100-full-time","WARC-Payload-Digest":"sha1:EQQK6ZQOFRLGTGL63JICAUOMIKG6LYVX","WARC-Block-Digest":"sha1:DB4Y2D2AW7FQMXJO77UTVUKAWKBE7QTB","WARC-Identified-Payload-Type":"text\/html"}},"annotations":{"Entities":[{"Mentions":[{"BeginOffset":0,"EndOffset":7,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.998105,"Text":"SEATTLE","Type":"LOCATION"},{"BeginOffset":245,"EndOffset":256,"GroupScore":0.997917,"Score":0.996401,"Text":"Minneapolis","Type":"LOCATION"},{"BeginOffset":913,"EndOffset":924,"GroupScore":0.633777,"Score":0.991507,"Text":"Minneapolis","Type":"LOCATION"},{"BeginOffset":930,"EndOffset":932,"GroupScore":0.377937,"Score":0.939713,"Text":"it","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":1014,"EndOffset":1025,"GroupScore":0.296383,"Score":0.995699,"Text":"Minneapolis","Type":"LOCATION"},{"BeginOffset":1252,"EndOffset":1263,"GroupScore":0.274503,"Score":0.996143,"Text":"Minneapolis","Type":"LOCATION"},{"BeginOffset":1325,"EndOffset":1336,"GroupScore":0.212837,"Score":0.997607,"Text":"Minneapolis","Type":"LOCATION"},{"BeginOffset":1358,"EndOffset":1369,"GroupScore":0.210503,"Score":0.843073,"Text":"Minneapolis","Type":"LOCATION"},{"BeginOffset":1521,"EndOffset":1532,"GroupScore":0.1735,"Score":0.945097,"Text":"Minneapolis","Type":"LOCATION"},{"BeginOffset":1970,"EndOffset":1981,"GroupScore":0.151855,"Score":0.984984,"Text":"Minneapolis","Type":"LOCATION"},{"BeginOffset":2026,"EndOffset":2037,"GroupScore":0.159188,"Score":0.899899,"Text":"Minneapolis","Type":"LOCATION"},{"BeginOffset":2233,"EndOffset":2244,"GroupScore":0.137462,"Score":0.936398,"Text":"Minneapolis","Type":"LOCATION"},{"BeginOffset":2368,"EndOffset":2379,"GroupScore":0.490252,"Score":0.998092,"Text":"Minneapolis","Type":"LOCATION"},{"BeginOffset":2824,"EndOffset":2835,"GroupScore":0.999818,"Score":0.997841,"Text":"Minneapolis","Type":"LOCATION"}]},{"Mentions":[{"BeginOffset":26,"EndOffset":38,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.999512,"Text":"Jun. 9, 2016","Type":"DATE"},{"BeginOffset":63,"EndOffset":68,"GroupScore":0.999904,"Score":0.999386,"Text":"today","Type":"DATE"}]},{"Mentions":[{"BeginOffset":41,"EndOffset":47,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.999652,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":219,"EndOffset":225,"GroupScore":0.999036,"Score":0.999013,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":268,"EndOffset":274,"GroupScore":0.512893,"Score":0.999449,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":352,"EndOffset":357,"GroupScore":0.348611,"Score":0.983583,"Text":"group","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":467,"EndOffset":473,"GroupScore":0.286059,"Score":0.999009,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":649,"EndOffset":655,"GroupScore":0.235291,"Score":0.999478,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":800,"EndOffset":806,"GroupScore":0.184027,"Score":0.999054,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":967,"EndOffset":969,"GroupScore":0.155309,"Score":0.998629,"Text":"We","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":1093,"EndOffset":1095,"GroupScore":0.149096,"Score":0.582519,"Text":"us","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":1149,"EndOffset":1155,"GroupScore":0.12771,"Score":0.99928,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":1311,"EndOffset":1317,"GroupScore":0.120431,"Score":0.998998,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":1471,"EndOffset":1477,"GroupScore":0.132681,"Score":0.999282,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":1701,"EndOffset":1707,"GroupScore":0.11731,"Score":0.999133,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":1722,"EndOffset":1728,"GroupScore":0.104673,"Score":0.998882,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":1804,"EndOffset":1811,"GroupScore":0.096387,"Score":0.998367,"Text":"company","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":1924,"EndOffset":1930,"GroupScore":0.089308,"Score":0.999335,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":2055,"EndOffset":2059,"GroupScore":0.080096,"Score":0.982571,"Text":"they","Type":"PERSON"},{"BeginOffset":2109,"EndOffset":2113,"GroupScore":0.073981,"Score":0.993249,"Text":"they","Type":"PERSON"},{"BeginOffset":2304,"EndOffset":2310,"GroupScore":0.416608,"Score":0.999578,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":2345,"EndOffset":2352,"GroupScore":0.258389,"Score":0.998698,"Text":"company","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":2423,"EndOffset":2429,"GroupScore":0.187167,"Score":0.99894,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":2653,"EndOffset":2659,"GroupScore":0.356525,"Score":0.999174,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":2775,"EndOffset":2781,"GroupScore":0.297722,"Score":0.99929,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":3117,"EndOffset":3123,"GroupScore":0.232355,"Score":0.999284,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":3272,"EndOffset":3278,"GroupScore":0.22839,"Score":0.999654,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":3342,"EndOffset":3346,"GroupScore":0.190797,"Score":0.733169,"Text":"them","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":3444,"EndOffset":3450,"GroupScore":0.169606,"Score":0.999676,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":3503,"EndOffset":3513,"GroupScore":0.153926,"Score":0.999821,"Text":"Amazon.com","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":3561,"EndOffset":3568,"GroupScore":0.135924,"Score":0.99842,"Text":"company","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":3821,"EndOffset":3827,"GroupScore":0.123618,"Score":0.999339,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":3891,"EndOffset":3897,"GroupScore":0.108615,"Score":0.71882,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":3965,"EndOffset":3971,"GroupScore":0.097442,"Score":0.999655,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"}]},{"Mentions":[{"BeginOffset":329,"EndOffset":339,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.990444,"Text":"Code Savvy","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":1907,"EndOffset":1908,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.966076,"Text":"I","Type":"PERSON"},{"BeginOffset":2008,"EndOffset":2020,"GroupScore":0.997444,"Score":0.999158,"Text":"Raymond Dehn","Type":"PERSON"},{"BeginOffset":2137,"EndOffset":2147,"GroupScore":0.998727,"Score":0.99657,"Text":"Code Savvy","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":2281,"EndOffset":2282,"GroupScore":0.803473,"Score":0.996255,"Text":"I","Type":"PERSON"},{"BeginOffset":2450,"EndOffset":2460,"GroupScore":0.7684,"Score":0.99944,"Text":"Code Savvy","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":2731,"EndOffset":2741,"GroupScore":0.503745,"Score":0.999295,"Text":"Code Savvy","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":2744,"EndOffset":2754,"GroupScore":0.445742,"Score":0.999775,"Text":"Code Savvy","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":2857,"EndOffset":2859,"GroupScore":0.301979,"Score":0.967544,"Text":"us","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":2971,"EndOffset":2981,"GroupScore":0.250808,"Score":0.998216,"Text":"Code Savvy","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":3033,"EndOffset":3043,"GroupScore":0.21858,"Score":0.999441,"Text":"Code Savvy","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":3087,"EndOffset":3089,"GroupScore":0.189786,"Score":0.998253,"Text":"we","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":3302,"EndOffset":3304,"GroupScore":0.190065,"Score":0.991269,"Text":"we","Type":"ORGANIZATION"}]},{"Mentions":[{"BeginOffset":585,"EndOffset":594,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.987979,"Text":"employees","Type":"PERSON"}]},{"Mentions":[{"BeginOffset":701,"EndOffset":719,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.982994,"Text":"software engineers","Type":"PERSON"}]},{"Mentions":[{"BeginOffset":1408,"EndOffset":1417,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.961828,"Text":"workforce","Type":"PERSON"}]}],"Events":[{"Arguments":[{"EntityIndex":1,"Role":"ANNOUNCEMENT_DATE","Score":0.999512},{"EntityIndex":2,"Role":"EMPLOYER","Score":0.999652},{"EntityIndex":4,"Role":"EMPLOYEE","Score":0.987979},{"EntityIndex":5,"Role":"EMPLOYEE","Score":0.982994},{"EntityIndex":0,"Role":"EMPLOYER","Score":0.939713},{"EntityIndex":6,"Role":"EMPLOYEE","Score":0.961828},{"EntityIndex":2,"Role":"EMPLOYEE","Score":0.982571}],"Triggers":[{"BeginOffset":159,"EndOffset":165,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.999996,"Text":"create","Type":"EMPLOYMENT_CHANGE"},{"BeginOffset":548,"EndOffset":554,"GroupScore":0.998411,"Score":0.999995,"Text":"hiring","Type":"EMPLOYMENT_CHANGE"},{"BeginOffset":723,"EndOffset":727,"GroupScore":0.550822,"Score":0.999995,"Text":"join","Type":"EMPLOYMENT_CHANGE"},{"BeginOffset":956,"EndOffset":965,"GroupScore":0.383564,"Score":0.998757,"Text":"expansion","Type":"EMPLOYMENT_CHANGE"},{"BeginOffset":984,"EndOffset":990,"GroupScore":0.283684,"Score":0.999995,"Text":"create","Type":"EMPLOYMENT_CHANGE"},{"BeginOffset":1300,"EndOffset":1307,"GroupScore":0.217834,"Score":0.619486,"Text":"welcome","Type":"EMPLOYMENT_CHANGE"},{"BeginOffset":1483,"EndOffset":1488,"GroupScore":0.200553,"Score":0.99819,"Text":"bring","Type":"EMPLOYMENT_CHANGE"},{"BeginOffset":1934,"EndOffset":1942,"GroupScore":0.163563,"Score":0.97419,"Text":"bringing","Type":"EMPLOYMENT_CHANGE"},{"BeginOffset":2063,"EndOffset":2071,"GroupScore":0.177144,"Score":0.999951,"Text":"creating","Type":"EMPLOYMENT_CHANGE"}],"Type":"EMPLOYMENT_CHANGE"},{"Arguments":[{"EntityIndex":2,"Role":"INVESTEE","Score":0.993249},{"EntityIndex":3,"Role":"INVESTEE","Score":0.99657},{"EntityIndex":0,"Role":"INVESTMENT_PLACE","Score":0.998092},{"EntityIndex":2,"Role":"INVESTOR","Score":0.99894},{"EntityIndex":3,"Role":"INVESTOR","Score":0.967544}],"Triggers":[{"BeginOffset":2127,"EndOffset":2133,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.950863,"Text":"donate","Type":"INVESTMENT_GENERAL"},{"BeginOffset":2438,"EndOffset":2446,"GroupScore":0.999946,"Score":0.971896,"Text":"donating","Type":"INVESTMENT_GENERAL"},{"BeginOffset":2464,"EndOffset":2468,"GroupScore":0.998101,"Score":0.992788,"Text":"fund","Type":"INVESTMENT_GENERAL"},{"BeginOffset":2867,"EndOffset":2875,"GroupScore":0.500723,"Score":0.906406,"Text":"donation","Type":"INVESTMENT_GENERAL"},{"BeginOffset":3078,"EndOffset":3085,"GroupScore":0.349069,"Score":0.997332,"Text":"funding","Type":"INVESTMENT_GENERAL"}],"Type":"INVESTMENT_GENERAL"},{"Arguments":[{"EntityIndex":2,"Role":"EMPLOYER","Score":0.999676}],"Triggers":[{"BeginOffset":3421,"EndOffset":3438,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.998136,"Text":"job opportunities","Type":"EMPLOYMENT_CHANGE"}],"Type":"EMPLOYMENT_CHANGE"}]},"preprocessing":{"level":"char","sentences":[{"start":0,"end":30,"index":0},{"start":31,"end":56,"index":1},{"start":57,"end":62,"index":2},{"start":63,"end":205,"index":3},{"start":206,"end":466,"index":4},{"start":467,"end":648,"index":5},{"start":648,"end":807,"index":6},{"start":808,"end":966,"index":7},{"start":967,"end":1226,"index":8},{"start":1226,"end":1356,"index":9},{"start":1357,"end":1489,"index":10},{"start":1490,"end":1517,"index":11},{"start":1517,"end":1721,"index":12},{"start":1722,"end":1906,"index":13},{"start":1906,"end":2039,"index":14},{"start":2040,"end":2232,"index":15},{"start":2233,"end":2276,"index":16},{"start":2277,"end":2284,"index":17},{"start":2285,"end":2330,"index":18},{"start":2330,"end":2510,"index":19},{"start":2511,"end":2652,"index":20},{"start":2653,"end":2743,"index":21},{"start":2743,"end":2955,"index":22},{"start":2956,"end":2993,"index":23},{"start":2994,"end":3044,"index":24},{"start":3045,"end":3217,"index":25},{"start":3218,"end":3297,"index":26},{"start":3298,"end":3401,"index":27},{"start":3401,"end":3503,"index":28},{"start":3503,"end":3556,"index":29},{"start":3557,"end":3732,"index":30},{"start":3733,"end":3972,"index":31},{"start":3973,"end":4022,"index":32}]},"char_count":4022}
{"raw_text":"Any European Software Developer or Business Now Has Easy Access to Highly Scalable, Reliable, Fast and Inexpensive Data Storage in the Cloud\nSEATTLE--(BUSINESS WIRE)--Nov. 6, 2007--Amazon Web Services today launched European storage for its popular Amazon Simple Storage Service (Amazon S3), allowing software developers and businesses to store their data in Europe. Amazon S3 is a storage service in the cloud offering software developers and businesses low-cost access to the same scalable and reliable storage infrastructure Amazon uses to run its own global network of web sites. Since its launch in March 2006, Amazon S3 has grown rapidly and now holds over 10 billion objects. Developers and businesses can build on Amazon S3 today at http:\/\/aws.amazon.com\/s3.\n\"Since the U.S. launch of Amazon S3, developers in Europe have asked us to add the ability to store data in Europe. They wanted the same high quality, low cost service, but with lower latency and local data storage. We've been working hard to make this a reality and are excited to offer Amazon S3 from European datacenters,\" said Adam Selipsky, Vice President of Product Management and Developer Relations for Amazon Web Services. \"We are actively working on other important requirements, such as accepting payment in Euros and providing local language support, but are pleased to offer a release that we think many European businesses and developers will find useful right now.\"\nAmazon S3 is storage for the Internet. It's designed to make web-scale computing easier for developers. Amazon S3 provides a simple web services interface that can be used to store and retrieve any amount of data, at any time, from anywhere on the web. The service gives any developer access to Amazon's data storage infrastructure and aims to maximize benefits of scale and to pass those benefits on to developers.\n\"We are very excited about the development of a European storage solution for Amazon S3,\" said Martin Gill, Head of New Media for Comic Relief, an organization committed to raising poverty awareness. \"Following a very successful 'test drive' of the US-hosted Amazon S3 service during our work supporting 'Idol Gives Back' last April, we saw this service being a core resource for the development of Comic Relief's digital vision for our UK fundraising activities. The US service stood up under substantial load and showed us just how affordable, easy to use, and scalable the service is. Without it we would have missed some great opportunities. Enormous scalability, combined with the legal benefits of holding data and assets within the EU, makes the European storage of Amazon S3 a brilliant early Christmas present for us!\"\n\"Amazon S3 is allowing us to store massive amounts of digital media in a trusted place and have a pay-as-you-go scheme at the same time,\" said Klaas Waslander, Chief Technical Officer for Albumprinter, a leading provider of personalized photo product solutions for retailers, internet companies and other photo channels in Europe and the US. \"When we thought about the fact that this is the same service that Amazon uses in its own retail operations it made us confident to use it in our own. With the availability of Amazon S3 from datacenters in Europe we are now able to use storage behind-the-scenes for all of our European customers, which is fantastic news for us.\"\nAmazon S3 lets developers pay only for what they consume and charges no up-front or minimum fee. The following are US$ prices for Amazon S3 in Europe:\nAmazon Web Services (AWS) provides technology services that give businesses access to Amazon's own-back technology infrastructure that they can use to enable virtually any type of business. These in-the-cloud web services make it possible for any business to reach the scale of major internet players such as Amazon.com, but without the expensive price tag these companies must pay to build and maintain such reliable, secure, and scalable infrastructure. Businesses can use AWS to achieve this level of web scale with zero up-front investment and low, pay-as-you-go pricing. More than 290,000 developers have signed up to use AWS since its inception. Amazon Web Services LLC is an Amazon.com company. More information is available at http:\/\/aws.amazon.com.\nAmazon.com, Inc., (Nasdaq: AMZN), a Fortune 500 company based in Seattle, opened on the World Wide Web in July 1995 and today offers Earth's Biggest Selection. Amazon.com seeks to be Earth's most customer-centric company, where customers can find and discover anything they might want to buy online, and endeavors to offer its customers the lowest possible prices. Amazon.com and other sellers offer millions of unique new, refurbished and used items in categories such as health and personal care, jewelry and watches, gourmet food, sports and outdoors, apparel and accessories, books, music, DVDs, electronics and office, toys and baby, and home and garden.\nAmazon and its affiliates operate websites, including www.amazon.com, www.amazon.co.uk, www.amazon.de, www.amazon.co.jp, www.amazon.fr, www.amazon.ca, and the Joyo Amazon websites at www.joyo.cn and www.amazon.cn.\nAs used herein, \"Amazon.com,\" \"we,\" \"our\" and similar terms include Amazon.com, Inc., and its subsidiaries, unless the context indicates otherwise.\nThis announcement contains forward-looking statements within the meaning of Section 27A of the Securities Act of 1933 and Section 21E of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934. Actual results may differ significantly from management's expectations. These forward-looking statements involve risks and uncertainties that include, among others, risks related to competition, management of growth, new products, services and technologies, potential fluctuations in operating results, international expansion, outcomes of legal proceedings and claims, fulfillment center optimization, seasonality, commercial agreements, acquisitions and strategic transactions, foreign exchange rates, system interruption, significant amount of indebtedness, inventory, government regulation and taxation, payments and fraud. More information about factors that potentially could affect Amazon.com's financial results is included in Amazon.com's filings with the Securities and Exchange Commission, including its Annual Report on Form 10-K for the year ended December 31, 2006, and all subsequent filings.","metadata":{"keywords":"acquisitions;investment","title":"Amazon Web Services Offers European Storage for Amazon S3","document_id":"69b078b1-2b1b-4c8f-b9ab-5220e0ea02bf","common_crawl":{"WARC":"1.0","WARC-Type":"response","WARC-Date":"2019-01-23T12:26:28Z","WARC-Record-ID":"<urn:uuid:962cb2ec-fbd3-48b1-a82e-db6318752e34>","Content-Length":"76085","Content-Type":"application\/http; msgtype=response","WARC-Warcinfo-ID":"<urn:uuid:008e0743-9d3c-4252-8654-4511893ad0bd>","WARC-Concurrent-To":"<urn:uuid:4598c0f7-5fce-4d40-8767-dd405c776ffc>","WARC-IP-Address":"23.46.239.49","WARC-Target-URI":"https:\/\/press.aboutamazon.com\/news-releases\/news-release-details\/amazon-web-services-offers-european-storage-amazon-s3","WARC-Payload-Digest":"sha1:YE6SBBOJEEETVZRNUYV3RTIUCJRZBHUY","WARC-Block-Digest":"sha1:B5BG5NZXOVTUMMQEAXB46OBXR6KSNSBX","WARC-Identified-Payload-Type":"text\/html"}},"annotations":{"Entities":[{"Mentions":[{"BeginOffset":2637,"EndOffset":2643,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.996633,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":2693,"EndOffset":2699,"GroupScore":0.992087,"Score":0.998109,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":3210,"EndOffset":3216,"GroupScore":0.492355,"Score":0.953989,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":3364,"EndOffset":3370,"GroupScore":0.351331,"Score":0.937688,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":3494,"EndOffset":3500,"GroupScore":0.240559,"Score":0.983006,"Text":"Amazon","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":3515,"EndOffset":3534,"GroupScore":0.177997,"Score":0.99595,"Text":"Amazon Web Services","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":3536,"EndOffset":3539,"GroupScore":0.932535,"Score":0.914972,"Text":"AWS","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":3990,"EndOffset":3993,"GroupScore":0.534979,"Score":0.999428,"Text":"AWS","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":4142,"EndOffset":4145,"GroupScore":0.348077,"Score":0.99916,"Text":"AWS","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":4167,"EndOffset":4190,"GroupScore":0.256725,"Score":0.999574,"Text":"Amazon Web Services LLC","Type":"ORGANIZATION"}]},{"Mentions":[{"BeginOffset":3580,"EndOffset":3590,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.994347,"Text":"businesses","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":3650,"EndOffset":3654,"GroupScore":0.999578,"Score":0.911424,"Text":"they","Type":"ORGANIZATION"},{"BeginOffset":3971,"EndOffset":3981,"GroupScore":0.516807,"Score":0.990188,"Text":"Businesses","Type":"ORGANIZATION"}]},{"Mentions":[{"BeginOffset":4109,"EndOffset":4119,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.762499,"Text":"developers","Type":"ORGANIZATION"}]}],"Events":[{"Arguments":[{"EntityIndex":1,"Role":"INVESTEE","Score":0.990188},{"EntityIndex":0,"Role":"INVESTEE","Score":0.999428}],"Triggers":[{"BeginOffset":4048,"EndOffset":4058,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.996232,"Text":"investment","Type":"INVESTMENT_GENERAL"}],"Type":"INVESTMENT_GENERAL"},{"Arguments":[{"EntityIndex":2,"Role":"EMPLOYEE","Score":0.762499},{"EntityIndex":0,"Role":"EMPLOYER","Score":0.99916}],"Triggers":[{"BeginOffset":4125,"EndOffset":4134,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.985596,"Text":"signed up","Type":"EMPLOYMENT_CHANGE"}],"Type":"EMPLOYMENT_CHANGE"},{"Arguments":[],"Triggers":[{"BeginOffset":5908,"EndOffset":5920,"GroupScore":1.0,"Score":0.999891,"Text":"acquisitions","Type":"CORPORATE_ACQUISITION"}],"Type":"CORPORATE_ACQUISITION"}]},"preprocessing":{"level":"char","sentences":[{"start":0,"end":43,"index":0},{"start":44,"end":141,"index":1},{"start":141,"end":171,"index":2},{"start":172,"end":366,"index":3},{"start":367,"end":583,"index":4},{"start":584,"end":682,"index":5},{"start":683,"end":767,"index":6},{"start":767,"end":882,"index":7},{"start":883,"end":982,"index":8},{"start":983,"end":1198,"index":9},{"start":1199,"end":1448,"index":10},{"start":1448,"end":1486,"index":11},{"start":1487,"end":1551,"index":12},{"start":1552,"end":1700,"index":13},{"start":1701,"end":1864,"index":14},{"start":1864,"end":2063,"index":15},{"start":2064,"end":2167,"index":16},{"start":2168,"end":2327,"index":17},{"start":2328,"end":2451,"index":18},{"start":2452,"end":2509,"index":19},{"start":2510,"end":2692,"index":20},{"start":2692,"end":3033,"index":21},{"start":3034,"end":3184,"index":22},{"start":3185,"end":3364,"index":23},{"start":3364,"end":3460,"index":24},{"start":3461,"end":3704,"index":25},{"start":3705,"end":3970,"index":26},{"start":3971,"end":4090,"index":27},{"start":4091,"end":4166,"index":28},{"start":4167,"end":4216,"index":29},{"start":4217,"end":4273,"index":30},{"start":4273,"end":4432,"index":31},{"start":4433,"end":4637,"index":32},{"start":4638,"end":4933,"index":33},{"start":4933,"end":5002,"index":34},{"start":5003,"end":5147,"index":35},{"start":5147,"end":5295,"index":36},{"start":5295,"end":5468,"index":37},{"start":5469,"end":5540,"index":38},{"start":5541,"end":6096,"index":39},{"start":6097,"end":6376,"index":40}]},"char_count":6376}
